It's been a few weeks since the Homunculi settled in Avancia.
这些人造人入住阿凡锡亚 已经过了几个礼拜
The much-anticipated public bathhouse is slowly taking shape.
众所期待的公共澡堂慢慢有了雏型
Although many residents
虽然有许多居民
worried about Homunculi staying in town,
担心人造人待在镇上会引发问题
they showed diligence…
但他们总是非常努力地工作
And their efforts
那副模样…
have garnered increasing support.
让赞扬他们的人也日渐增多
Meanwhile,
至于我呢
Demon Lord Greed could come and claim the life of the strongest, me,
因为魔王葛利德
at any moment,
到那时候…
and I must be prepared for it.
我必须战胜他才行
My senses must be sharpened.
要让感官更加敏锐才行
What an adorable baby!
这孩子真可爱
BAYBERN
（贝邦）
It would cost 70,000 points to get this monster in a normal lottery.
若用普通的转蛋方式 可是要花七万点才能得到的魔物
You hit the jackpot, Nin!
妮恩 你赚到了
I got a little fairy.
我这边抽到了妖精
LUFIA
（路菲亚）
Oh, it's a devil fairy.
是小妖精啊
It should come in handy.
这家伙也能派上用场
thanks for letting us use the points.
谢谢你让我们用点数
Thanks to you, I have a new cute little companion.
多亏了你 我做出了一个可爱的搭档
Speaking of which,
话说回来
being the labyrinth manager is really something.
迷宫管理者还真厉害呢
You've gotten so close to the monsters.
居然可以和魔物这么亲近
They weren't affectionate with me at all
我负责管理时
when I was overseeing the labyrinth.
明明都不愿意亲近我
Well, their love is a little suffocating.
我倒是觉得它们太黏我了
OPENING DAY OF THE PUBLIC BATHHOUSE
（公共澡堂开幕日）
Today,
今天起公共澡堂将正式营业
The Homunculi built this, right?
这是人造人建的吧？
Is it really okay to go inside?
没问题吗？
Though the reactions of the residents remain split…
镇上居民的反应还是不太好呢
Is that the rumored public bathhouse?
这就是传闻中的公共澡堂吗？
Homunculi are amazing!
人造人太强啦
We'll be the first group of customers to try it out.
我们会先作为第一组顾客进去体验
Please look forward to it.
还请大家敬请期待
I'm heading in.
我先进去啦
Is this really all right?
真的没问题吗？
It's been a long time since I've been in such a beautiful bath.
我好久没有泡过这种漂亮的澡堂了
Demon Lords bathe too?
魔王们也会洗澡吗？
Of course.
当然会啊
What do you take us for?
你把我们想成什么人了啊？
We are no different than humans in this regard.
在这部分 我们跟普通人没什么两样
I see.
这样啊
By the way, where's Luna?
话说回来 露娜呢？
She says she's not used to showing her body around others.
那孩子说她不习惯 让人看到自己的身体
Is that so?
这样啊
But perhaps one day she'll come around.
不过或许总有一天就会习惯了
Let's invite her to join us when she's ready.
到时候再拉她一起来泡澡吧
Yes, that's the plan.
好啊 我也是这么打算的
All right!
好了
Let's get in and enjoy the bath!
那我们赶紧去享受一下吧
Indeed.
好
It's quite spacious inside.
话说回来 里面还真宽敞呢
Lilia, let's wash each other.
姐姐 我们互相帮彼此洗澡吧
Don't play with bubbles as you wash!
不要边说边用泡泡玩啊！
All right. Let's do it too, Manicia!
好 我们也来做吧 玛妮西娅
I've always wanted to bathe with a friend too.
我也一直很想那样
Well, if you don't mind…
那么如果你不介意的话…
All right!
好耶！
Wait…
等等
I want to join too!
也来洗我啦
Oh, whatever should I do?
该怎么办才好呢？
The water's quite warm.
热水还挺烫的呢
Don't swim in the bath!
不能在这里游泳啦
Incidentally, Nin,
话说回来 妮恩
you were taught transformation magic in my class.
你明明在我的魔法教室学了变身魔法
It's a shame there isn't a mixed bath.
这里却没有混浴 真是可惜呢
Amon!
等等 亚蒙
We agreed to keep that a secret!
不是说好那件事要保密的吗？
What kind of transformation magic do you plan to use in the bath?
你打算在混浴 用什么样的变身魔法呢？
Magic to increase the size of one's bosom…
-当然是要把胸部… -亚蒙
Finish that sentence
你再说下去
and I'll add the vegetables you hate to your meals every day.
我就每餐都在你的饭菜里 加你最讨厌的蔬菜喔
What? That would be awful!
什么？那样我会很困扰的！
Is it because among the women close to Rud,
难道是因为与路德亲近的女性中
I am the most full-bosomed, so you're jealous of me?
我的胸部最大 所以你才嫉妒我？
What?
什么？
We heard that.
我都听到了喔
Allow us to verify.
让我好好确认一下吧
W… Wait!
等等
So soft!
-好软喔！ -放开我！
This is to punish you for saying unnecessary things.
这是为了惩罚你说了多余的话
This is something Lilia doesn't have.
这是姐姐没有的东西呢
Lily! Don't make unnecessary comments!
莉莉 不要说些有的没的
I was wrong! Please forgive me!
我知道错了 原谅我吧！
Something the matter, Manicia?
玛妮西娅 怎么了吗？
Not at all.
没事
I'm just happy
只是很高兴
that I can finally play with others like this.
因为自己终于也能像这样 和其他人一起玩耍了
Your condition's a lot better now, right?
你的身体应该好很多了吧？
Yes.
是的
Then, you'll have plenty of opportunities to try all sorts of things in the future.
那么今后肯定还有很多机会
I hope so.
是吗？
Please!
拜托通融一下吧！
It's my one and only request!
这是我一生的请求！
It's rather noisy in the men's bath.
不觉得男汤那边有点吵吗？
We're begging you, Rud!
拜托你了 路德！
A little peek wouldn't hurt, right?
稍微偷看一下也没关系吧？
I'll just make a small hole in the wall.
我只会在墙壁上开个小洞而已！
Absolutely not!
当然不行啊
Manicia's there too!
玛妮西娅也在那边
And why are you trying to peek as well, Marius?
话说玛里乌斯为什么也想偷看啊？
I don't care about the view.
看不看对我来说都没差别
I just enjoy the thrill of it!
我只是喜欢这种惊险的紧张感！
Don't be so blatant!
别说得这么冠冕堂皇！
Please!
拜托了 我想看莉莉小姐的胸部啊！
I want to see Manicia's…
我想看玛妮西…
Are they trying to peek into the women's bath?
难道他们是想偷看女汤吗？
I'll kill them!
-看我杀了他们！ -等等
Amon, help me hold her back!
亚蒙 帮我拉住她啊！
Rud!
路德
We're all men here.
既然我们都是男的
There's no point in wasting time arguing!
就别再这里争来争去了
Exactly! Just to add, I want to see Lady Nin's!
是啊
I know she's flat, but I still want to see them!
虽然她是平胸 但我还是想看！
Who said that?
刚才那句话是谁说的？
Miss Nin, please calm down.
妮恩小姐 请你冷静一点
Enough!
你们给我适可而止！
Listen up.
听好了
All the girls you've been talking about are pretty much the same size!
你们刚才说的女孩 每个人尺寸都差不多
Stick to your fantasies and behave yourselves!
给我靠妄想乖乖忍耐
Rud, how did you find the bath?
路德 澡堂还可以吗？
It was amazing.
超棒的喔
Though, the adventurers were a lot to handle.
只是为了制止那些冒险者 害我费了一番心力
Rud.
路德
Anything dangerous inside?
里面没有什么危险的东西吧？
Not at all. It was…
没有 真的很…
That felt great.
真的超舒服的呢
The neighboring country's bath temperature is perfect.
-是啊 -邻国的洗澡水真的很热呢
I could get addicted to it.
感觉会泡上瘾
And the handmade soap is fantastic.
还有那个手工肥皂也超棒的
You heard them.
你看
Those adventurers looked like they enjoyed themselves too.
那些刚出来的冒险者们也很高兴吧？
Um…
那个…
We await your patronage,
我们会随时等着你们的
so please come and try it someday.
所以请你们一定要来光顾喔
Got it.
好 我知道了
Those men seemed to have good reviews for the bath.
刚才去泡澡的人反应好像很不错
Let's give it a try too.
我们也去泡泡看吧
Is the fragrance on adventurers
冒险者身上的香味
from the handmade soap they mentioned?
就是他刚才说的手工肥皂吗？
Mother, let's try it too.
妈妈 我们也去泡泡看吧
Please come and try it.
还请各位务必来试试看
Let's try it too.
那我们去泡泡看吧
Manicia, did you enjoy the bath?
玛妮西娅 泡得还舒服吗？
Yes, the bath was enjoyable…
澡堂确实很舒服
But somehow,
不过呢
it feels like all of us were insulted.
总觉得我们好像被一并嘲笑了
Wow, that was a great bath.
哎呀 泡得真舒服啊
Oh, if it isn't the girls used in our fantasies?
这不是方便用来妄想的女孩子们吗？
Lily.
莉莉
On it, Lilia.
好的 姐姐
-Fusion.
-技能 融合
A FEW DAYS LATER
（几天后）
Thank you, everyone,
各位 谢谢你们帮忙盖了公共澡堂
I enjoyed a nice bath.
我泡得很舒服喔
Thank you very much.
谢谢你们
With this public bathhouse,
多亏了这个公共澡堂
the folks in town and the Homunculi have gotten a lot closer.
镇上居民和人造人之间的距离 缩短了许多
Please come again.
欢迎您再次光临
Samimina.
萨米弥娜
Thank you for reaching out to humans.
谢谢你愿意主动亲近人类
This is for my own sake.
这是为了我自己
And you have been kind to us.
而且路德对我们也有恩
Even so, thank you.
即便如此 也很谢谢你
Rud!
路德！
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Another fight between the adventurers?
又有冒险者打起来了吗？
A massive horde of monsters
有一群数量多到吓人的魔物
is heading towards Avancia!
朝阿凡锡亚过来了！
I heard there's a large group of monsters coming towards the town.
听说有一大群魔物朝镇上过来了
The guild seems to have issued an urgent request to adventurers.
公会好像也向冒险者们 发出了紧急委托
After all, the vigilante corps alone can't stop them.
毕竟光靠自警团应该挡不下来
With so many folks gathered, we'll overcome this.
聚集了这么多人 应该就能度过难关了吧
Everyone.
各位！
We're up against over 150 monsters, but there's no need to fret,
虽然我们要对抗的 是超过150只的魔物大军
as we are equally matched.
因为我们的战力也跟它们差不多
Is that right?
是这样吗？
You are aware we conquered that labyrinth.
大家应该也知道 我们攻略过哪个迷宫吧？
Yes.
没错
We conquered Keild Labyrinth, the one the two major clans failed.
我们攻略了两大战团
Adventurers fortunate enough to participate in this battle
能参加这场战斗的冒险者非常幸运
will receive generous rewards
因为你们只要打倒一只魔物
for defeating the monsters.
就能得到相当优渥的报酬
Now, will you accept our request?
那么有人要接受我们的紧急委托吗？
Nice pitch.
你真会说服别人
Reminds me of the ball in Keild.
-让我想起凯路德的舞会 -有路德在稳赢的吧
I did understate the numbers.
-虽然我稍微少报了数量 -听说露娜也很厉害喔
There must be about 300 of them.
-其实有300只左右吧 -那对双胞胎也会参加吧
If it's over 100, everyone will lose count.
只要超过100只 大家就分不清楚实际的数量了
And you just have to defeat all of them.
而且只要路德努力多打倒几只就行了
Rud, do you have a moment?
路德 你现在有空吗？
I sense an unpleasant presence.
我感受到一股讨厌的气息
It seems a new labyrinth has appeared nearby.
这附近好像出现了一个新的迷宫
A new labyrinth?
新的迷宫？
And it's a formidable one at that.
而且是个相当厉害的迷宫
Could those monsters be connected to the new Labyrinth?
难道那群魔物跟新的迷宫有关连吗？
It's a probability.
有可能
Though it's just my speculation.
虽然只是我的猜测
But they must have cloned the monsters
对方应该是让迷宫里的魔物进行分身
in the labyrinth and sent them out.
再送到外面来
Yes.
可以
So there might be even more monsters than accounted for.
所以魔物应该还会变得更多
Got it.
我知道了
You shall have the support of my magic.
我会用魔法支援你们的
I'll be at the frontline cutting them down too.
我当然也会在前线狠狠斩杀它们
We'll support you too.
我们也来一起帮忙
Rud saved us that day.
那天是路德救了我们
Wield me as your sword.
为了你 我会成为你的剑
Let us protect this town together.
一起守护这座城镇吧
Samimina, everyone…
萨米弥娜 各位…
Baybern and Lufia! Do you two want to help too?
贝邦和路菲亚也想帮忙吗？
I have just the job for you guys.
那正好 我有事想拜托你们
This should strengthen our defense as much as possible.
还来得及尽可能加强防护
The monsters are in sight!
可以看到魔物了！
Raise your weapons!
所有人拿起武器
Release your long-range magic and skills when the monsters are close!
魔物靠近时
Jeez… that's more than 300 monsters!
-喂 -那些魔物超过300只了吧
This doesn't look good…
这样不太妙
Don't back down!
别退缩！
Look! The group of monsters at the front are just Goblins.
快看
No need to be afraid.
我们没必要害怕
Attack!
攻击！
Looks like we took down quite a lot.
好像打倒挺多只的耶
What's the deal with those monsters?
那些魔物是怎么回事啊？
Those Goblins can use magic!
那些哥布林会用魔法！
This is bad!
不妙啊
Those aren't normal monsters! We should run…
那些家伙果然不是普通的魔物！
Ready?
-快逃… -准备好了吗？
Fusion complete. Leave it to us.
融合完毕 交给我们吧
All right. Let's do this.
那我们上吧
Taunt!
挑衅！
He managed to use Taunt on all the monsters!
居然对所有魔物施展了挑衅！
Using mana to strengthen the body.
通过魔力强化肉体
Straight to the center!
一口气冲到中心了
Mister Rud is incredible!
路德先生太强了
Rud, behind you--
路德 小心后面！
I'm fine.
我没事
I see everything.
我全都看得到
Impressive.
好厉害
That lad
那家伙用魔力掌握了所有状况吗？
Let's continue the attack.
我们也继续攻击吧
All right. We took care of them all.
很好 这下就全部解决了
This is all thanks to Rud diverting the attention of the monsters.
多亏了路德引开魔物们的注意力
That guy is really strong.
那家伙真的超强的
Your shield force's been fully restored.
护盾回复完毕了
Thanks.
谢谢你
After they died, they all disappeared,
敌人死掉后全都消失了
which means
也就是说那些魔物 真的是从迷宫里出来的吗？
What in the world is going on?
这到底是怎么一回事？
Here they come again!
又来了！
Another wave of different monsters incoming!
又有一群不一样的魔物过来了！
We just defeated so many.
明明才刚打倒那么多魔物 居然还有？
There are even Ogres this time!
这次连食人魔都来了！
Remain calm.
大家冷静一点
B-but…
可是…
Don't worry.
别担心
We will be
我们绝对会赢的！
Another wave incoming!
又来了一群魔物！
Chameleon Kong and Fieldsaurus!
变色龙金刚和菲尔多龙！
Why are the monsters in the labyrinth here?
为什么迷宫的魔物会跑来这里？
I can't fight anymore…
我不行了！
They're attacking the other monsters?
魔物在攻击魔物？
What's going on?
这到底是怎么回事？
Finally!
终于来了啊
Duplicate as many of the Avancia Labyrinth monsters as you can
帮我尽可能地 复制阿凡锡亚迷宫的魔物
and bring them here to support us.
并带它们过来支援我们
It seems like things are going smoothly on Lufia and Baybern's side.
看来路菲亚和贝邦进行得很顺利呢
The monsters from the Avancia Labyrinth are now under my control.
阿凡锡亚迷宫的魔物现在受我支配
They are our reinforcements.
它们是我们的援军
Reinforcements?
援军？
Is that for real?
真的假的啊？
I will charge into the enemy along with the monsters.
我会和魔物们一起冲进敌军中心
Support me as you did earlier.
你们就像刚才那样支援我
Taunt!
挑衅！
Mister Rud is surrounded by Ogres!
路德先生被食人魔包围了
That doesn't look good!
那样不太妙吧
Labyrinth monsters actually coming to aid humans…
迷宫的魔物居然来帮人类
This is unheard of. I can't believe my eyes!
实在是强大到超出我的理解范围了
Mister Rud, you're amazing!
路德先生太厉害了！
I didn't know you were so strong!
没想到你那么强
No, if it weren't for everyone's help, I wouldn't have defeated them.
不 要是没有大家的帮忙 我也没办法撑过去
Thank you all for your hard work.
各位辛苦了
I brought some spinach.
我带了一些菠菜过来喔
Come to me if you're injured.
受伤的人可以来找我
I'll repair everyone's damaged weapons for free.
我免费帮大家修复坏掉的武器
That was a magnificent battle.
这仗打得真漂亮啊
Amon.
亚蒙
To think you would use
没想到你居然可以和敌人一样
the opponent's trick against them.
靠复制迷宫的魔物撑过难关
I just thought
只是想说既然敌人做得到 我们应该也可以
But more than that,
不过比起这个
Such a dangerous labyrinth that releases a horde of monsters
像这样会放出大量魔物的危险迷宫
must not be overlooked.
我绝不能放任不管
Indeed.
是啊
If it is him, he'll definitely release even more monsters next time.
如果是那家伙 下次肯定会放出更多魔物吧
Him?
“那家伙”？
The new labyrinth is most likely
那个新的迷宫恐怕是
the work of Demon Lord Greed.
魔王葛利德的迷宫
Demon Lord Greed…
魔王葛利德
I sense his mana in the area.
我在附近感受到了那家伙的魔力
Then…
那么…
we have to get to Greed's labyrinth as soon as possible.
只能尽快攻略葛利德的迷宫
We must stop him from creating such disturbances again.
让他无法再惹出这种骚动才行
Rud…
路德
What do you plan to do after defeating Greed?
打败葛利德后 你打算怎么做？
Do you intend to extend an invitation to him as you did with me?
该不会又像象邀请我那样 让他成为我们的同伴吧？
I'm not sure if I should let him join us.
我也不知道是否该让他成为同伴
After all, I can't forgive him.
毕竟我没办法原谅他
The Homunculi must hate him, too.
人造人他们应该也很讨厌他
Are you going to kill him?
那你要杀了他吗？
Greed is the only one who knows
关于布伦凯斯国
the situation in Brunn Quelez.
有些情报只有葛利德知道
I'd like to capture him alive.
可以的话 我想活捉他
In that case, use these.
那么你可以用这个
These cuffs can seal the power of a Demon Lord.
这个手铐可以封印魔王的能力
It's similar to the slave bracelet I mentioned.
有点像我之前说的奴隶手环
It should be useful when you raid his labyrinth.
去攻略他的迷宫时应该可以派上用场
Thank you for all your help.
谢谢你帮我这么多
My pleasure.
不客气
I do quite enjoy my life here.
毕竟我在这边生活得很开心
No.
不
This time, I'll go with Nin, Luna, Lilia, Lily,
这次就让我 妮恩、露娜、莉莉亚、莉莉
Samimina will be a valuable asset to the team.
萨米弥娜的能力足以作为我们的战力
I want to put her powers to use in the Greed Labyrinth.
我希望她也能 把那份力量发挥在葛利德迷宫
Understood.
我知道了
What's the meaning of this, Rud?
这是什么意思？路德
Why am I being left out?
为什么把我排除在外？
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I want you to stay here and lead the adventurers.
我希望你能留在镇上 指挥剩下的冒险者
Amon will be in charge of the magic support team.
亚蒙则负责指挥魔法支援队
No, I want to fight too!
不要 我也想战斗！
I realized something back then.
在刚才的战斗中 我发现了一件事
Sending out the monsters was part of Greed's strategy.
葛利德是有计划地把魔物送过来的
So even after we go in to conquer the labyrinth,
所以在我们进去攻略迷宫后
he'll send more monsters.
他可能还会派魔物过来
You are closer to the adventurers,
你毕竟和冒险者们比较亲近
and as the subleader of the clan, you are trusted by everyone.
身为战团的副团长也深受我的信赖
I can only entrust such a dangerous battlefield to you.
目前这个危险的战场
All right. Let's do that then.
那么这次就先这样吧
Don't worry about things here.
你不必担心这边的状况
Whatever comes,
不管来的是什么 我都会把它们全部打倒的
Leave the support command to me.
后援的指挥就交给我吧
Thank you both.
谢谢你们两位
After the battle just now,
经过刚才的战斗
we've confirmed that a new labyrinth has emerged nearby.
我们确认附近出现了新的迷宫
So, we're going to raid that labyrinth.
所以我们接下来会去攻略那个迷宫
If monsters come to attack again,
如果之后又有魔物过来袭击
please protect the town together with Avancia's monsters.
还请你们和阿凡锡亚的魔物 一起守护这座城镇
Um…
那个…
Yes?
怎么了？
Is Demon Lord Greed
魔王葛利德真的在 接下来要攻略的迷宫里吗？
I'm afraid so.
恐怕是的
You know who Greed is, right?
你知道葛利德是谁吧？
Of course.
那当然
Among the Homunculi, there's no one who hasn't heard his name.
人造人里 没有人没听过他的名字
I see.
这样啊
Don't force yourself.
但是不要太逞强喔
Yes.
是
What's with this labyrinth?
这个迷宫是怎么回事？
There's nothing here.
居然什么东西都没有
I'll search the area with my magic.
我用探知魔法确认一下
There's really nothing here.
这里似乎真的什么都没有
Let's move to the next level, then.
那我们去找下一层吧
There doesn't appear
关于这个
to be a magic circle that leads to the next floor either.
我也没搜到通往下一层的魔法阵
What?
什么？
That means…
也就是说
this is the lowest floor of the labyrinth?
这里就是迷宫的最下层了吗？
Such intense mana!
这股强大的魔力是怎么回事？
There's no need for such hostility.
请不要如此杀气腾腾的
My name is Greed.
我的名字叫葛利德